Finding Aid for the Farington Family Correspondence LSC.0668
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Folio 13
  - Correspondence to William Farington and George Farington, 1799 November 08 - 1801 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Many of the letters are addressed to either William or George Farington aboard the HMS La Topaze in Jamaica, or to William aboard the HMS Plover.
    Some letters will include a salutation such as "Dear children" from mother Ann Farington, indicating that it is meant for both George and William Farington.
    The letter dated March 28, 1801 from sister E.F. Farington to George contains transcriptions of two poems, one entitled "Ho[p?] Garden" (which begins with "what sounds of mirth / Burst from that tavern, o'er whose ample gate / The portrait of celebrious naval chief...") and the second a selection from Robert Southey's "St. Juan Gualberto" (1800) which begins with the line "Slow sunk the glorious sun, a roseate light".
    The letter dated May 31, 1801 from sister E.F. Farington to George contains a transcription of a poem entitled "Mamma Mia".
- Folio 14
  - Binder Boards, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Roster of Warfield School, 1833 March (Box 6, Folder 1)
    "A List of the boys of Warfield School, March 1833", divided into four classes. R. Farington is in the Fourth Class.
  - Correspondence to Richard A. Farington while at Rev. R. Faithfull's in Warfield, 1833 January 25 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Two letters to Richard A. Farington while at Rev. R. Faithfull's in Warfield, one from a young sibling, [Edward?] Farington, and the other from Richard's mother as well as a sibling.
  - Correspondence to Edmund Farington, 1829 November 30 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    A small piece of correspondence addressed to Edmund Farington from his friend P. [?]asson.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1832 November 17 - 1840 June 26 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    11 letters or letter fragments addressed to William Farington from his brother Edmund Francis Farington, and mother Frances Anne Faringon, (father?) William Farington.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1834 March 20 - 1837 August 31 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    13 letters or letter fragments addressed to William Farington from his mother, Frances Anne Farington, brother Edmund Farington, and father William Farington.
  - Correspondence to Edmund Farington, 1831 January 27 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    The letter dated January 27, 1831 is from Edmund Farington's mother Frances A. Farington, and the undated later is from William Farington.
  - Correspondence to Richard Farington, 1833 February 13 - June 11 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    The letter dated February 13, 1833 is from Richard's mother Frances A. Farington, sister F.A. Farington, and William Farington. The letter dated June 11, 1833 is from Richard's father William Farington.
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1835 March 28 - April 02 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    The letter fragment dated March 28, 1835 is from William Farington's father, William, and the letter dated April 2, 1835 is from William Farington's mother, Frances A. Farington.
  - Correspondence to Edmund and Richard Farington, 1831 November 07 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    This letter is addressed to Richard Farington from William Farington, and also contains a note to Edmund Farington from his grandmother "C. Green".
  - Correspondence to William Farington, 1835 May 12 - 1840 July 21 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    The letters are addressed to William Farington from his father William Farington, mother Frances Ann Farington, sister Frances Ann Farington, brother Richard A. Farington, and brother Edmund Farington.
  - Correspondence to Edmund and Richard Farington, 1830 November 30 - 1831 November 30 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    These letters are addressed to Edmund Farington from his father William Farington, mother Frances Ann Farington, sister Frances Ann Farington and brother William Farington.
    The letter dated September 28, 1831 contains a note to Richard Farington ("Dicky")from their mother Frances Ann Farington, and the letter dated November 30, 1831 contains a note from father William Farington to Richard as well.
  - Correspondence to William Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Both letters are to William Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington. One letter is dated "Oct. 18" and the other is dated "Oct."
  - Correspondence to Richard Farington, 1833 March 13 - May 22 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    These letters are to Richard "Dick" Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington, brother Edmund, and sister Frances Ann.
  - Correspondence to Edmund Farington, 1830 July 23 - October 11 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    These letters are to Edmund Farington from his mother, Frances Ann Farington and possibly his father, William Farington (the signature on the letter dated September 24, 1830 is unclear).
  - Correspondence to Edmund and Richard Farington, 1830 November 12 - 1834 October 15 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    The letter dated November 12, 1830 is to Edmund Farington from his father William Farington.
    The letter dated October 19, 1831 contains correspondence to Richard Farington from his sister Frances Ann Farington and to Edmund Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington.
    The letter dated October 15, 1834 is to Richard Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington.
  - Correspondence to Edmund Farington from his mother Frances Ann Farington, 1833 June 14 - September 9 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Richard A. Farington Correspondence, 1837 November 13 - 1838 May 17 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    These letter are all addressed to Richard A. Farington from his mother, Frances A. Farington, sister Frances A. Farington, and father William Farington, except for a letter dated November 13, 1837, which is from Richard A. Farington to his father, Capt. Farington. The small note is from mother Frances A. Farington recommending to her son the use of a dictionary to correct his spelling.
  - Correspondence to Capt. Farington, RN and Edmund Farington, 1837 May 03 - August 18 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    The letter dated May 3, 1837 is addressed to Capt. Farington, RN from F.A. Farington; the letter with the postal stamp August 18, 1837 is addressed to Edmund Farington from his father William Farington and probably also from his mother.
  - Correspondence to Richard A. "Dick" Farington and Francis Ann "Fanny" Farington, 1835 April [?]6 - September 10 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    The folder contains 4 letters to Dick Farington:
    one dated Sept. 10, 1835 from father William,
    one dated April [?]6, 18[3?]5 from Edmund Farington,
    and two undated letters, one from sister Frances and one from mother Frances Farington. Tucked inside of the letter dated April [?]6, 18[3?]5 is a letter to Fanny Farington ("Mrs. Farington") from "brother" Edmund dated July [10?], [1835?].
  - Correspondence to Capt. Farington, RN, 1839 July 28 - September 28 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    The letter dated September 10, 1839 is from his friend [J.?] Ba[?]; the letter dated July 28, 1839 is from L.F. Ball.
  - Correspondence to Edmund and Richard Farington, 1828 November 11 - 1829 May 29 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    All of the letters are addressed to Edmund Farington from the following family members: brother William, sister Frances Ann "Fanny", mother Frances Ann Farington, and father William Farington. The letter dated May 25, 1829 includes a note from sister Fanny to both "Edmund and Dick".
  - Correspondence to Richard A. Farington, 1833 June 08 - 1835 December 10 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    All of the 21 letters in this folder are addressed to Richard A. Farington ("Dick") from one or more of the following family members: brother Edmund, brother William, sister Fanny, mother Frances Ann Farington, and father William Farington.
    Two letters (March 22, 1835 and undated) are tucked inside the letter dated "March 22", and one letter (March 1, 1835) is tucked inside the letter from Richard's mother Frances, also dated March 1, 1835.
    In addition to these letters, there is also a single sheet of pencil-ruled paper containing a school exercise entitled "On the instinct of animals".
  - Correspondence to Richard A. Farington, 1836 February 23 - 1837 December 08 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    All 32 of the letters in this folder are addressed to Richard A. Farington ("Dick") from one or more of the following family members: brother Edmund, brother William, sister Fanny, mother Frances Ann Farington, and father William Farington. The letter dated September 28, 1837 has a rough sketch of a guard in it.
  - Farington Family Correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    One undated letter from William Farington to his "Sons" that has no address or postal stamp.